Finding Aid for the Ernst Toch Papers PASC-M.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Music Manuscripts, Series 7.
  - Die Rollen des Schauspielers Seami, Holograph score 7 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 in (Box 120, Folder 4)
  - Turandot; Die Raeuber, Holograph score 11 p.; 10 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 120, Folder 5)
    Two works bound together.
  - Die Heilige von U.S.A., Holograph score 58 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 6)
  - Koenig Oedipus, Tiel 1, Holograph score 20 p.; 10 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 7)
  - Koenig Oedipus, Tiel II, Holograph score 26p.; 10 1/2 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 8)
  - Das Kirschbluetenfest, Holograph score 30 p.; 10 1/2 x 14 in. (Box 120, Folder 9)
  - Anabasis, Holograph score pp. 1-12; 10 1/2 x 12 i/2 in. (Box 120, Folder 10)
  - Napoleon, Holograph score pp. 13-36; 10 1/2 x 12 1/2 in. (Box 120, Folder 10)
  - Uli Wittewuepp, Holograph 58 p.; 10 3/4 x 13 in. (Box 120, Folder 11)
  - Gates of Carven Jade, Holograph score 8 p.; 11 x 14 1/2 in. (Box 120, Folder 12)
    Incomplete?
  - Streichquartett in A-moll, op. 12, photocopy of copyist's score, 48 p. (Box 120, Folder 13)
  - None Shall Escape, Holograph score, 216 p. (Box 121, Folder 1)
  - Address Unknown, Holograph score 171 p; 13 x 19 in. (Box 121, Folder 2)
  - Scheherazade [The Last Tale, Op. 88]. Parts. (Box 122, Folder unknown container)
    Note: Materials pertaining to premiere can be found in box 117, Realia and Miscellaneous.
  - The Last Tale, Op. 88. Drafts, sketches, libretti, etc. (Box 123, Folder unknown container)
    To be found among letter boxes.
- Toch Published Works, Series 8.
  Boxes 124-127. Printed publications by Ernst Toch.
  - Musical Works, Subseries 1.
    Printed publications of music by Ernst Toch.
    - Collected Works, miniature scores (Box 124, Folder 1)
      The Chinese flute for soprano and chamber orchestra, op. 29. New York: Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1949 (54 p.) -- Pinocchio. New York: Associated Music Publishers, Inc., 1937. (30 p.) -- String quartet op. 70. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, 1949. (42 p.) -- Hyperion, a dramatic prelude, op. 71. New York: Leeds Music Corporation, 1950. (62 p.) -- Erste Symphonie, op. 72. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1951. (183 p.).
    - Second Symphony, Op. 73, 1953; 140 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 2)
      Study score.
    - Erste Symphonie op. 72. Partitur, 1951; 183 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Erste Symphonie op. 72. Partitur., 1951; 183 pages; Miniature score, hardback (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Collected Works, miniature scores (Box 124, Folder 5)
      Quartet, op. 18 Leipzig: Josef Weinberger, 1911. (62 p.) -- Serenade, op. 20 fuer drei violinen. [Leipzig: Josef Weinberger, 1912. (29 p.) -- Streichquartett C-dur, op. 26. Coeln am Rhine: Tischer & Jagenberg, 1919?. (48 p.) -- Streichquartett auf den namen "Bass", op. 28. Coeln am Rhine: Tischer & Jagenberg, 1922? (51 p.) -- Quartett, op. 34. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1924. (53 p.).
    - Fuenf stuecke fuer kammerorchester, op. 33, 1924; 55 pages; miniature score, hardback (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Streichquartett auf den namen "Bass", op. 28, 1922?; 51 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Streichquartett C-dur, op. 26, 1919?; 48 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 8)
    - Symphony no. 2, Op. 73, 1953; 140 pages; Miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Symphony no. 4, op. 80, 1960; 56 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - Jephta, Rhapsodic Poem (Symphony No. 5), op. 89, 1965; 55 pages; miniature score, paperback (Box 124, Folder 11)
    - A watermelon, Avatiach, 1939; 2 pages; score (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - Der Faecher, 1930; 261 pages; piano reduction, hardcover (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Das Wasser, 1930; 43 pages; score, hardcover (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Poems to Martha, Op. 66, 1943; 39 pages; score, hardcover (Box 125, Folder 4)
    - Collected Works (Box 125, Folder 5)
      Konzert fuer violoncell un kammerorchester, op. 35. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1925. (Piano reduction, 37 p.) -- Zwei divertimenti fuer streichduo, op. 37. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, n.d. (24 p.) -- Konzert fuer klavier und orchester, op. 38. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1926. (Piano reduction, 71 p.) -- Neun Lieder fuer Sopran und Klavier, op. 41. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1928. (27 p.) -- Sonate fuer violine und klavier, op. 44. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1928. (23 p.) -- Sonate fuer violoncello und klavier, op. 50. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1929. (20 p.).
    - Fanal fuer Orchester und Orgel, op. 45, 1928; 16 pages; score, hardcover (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Kleine Theater-Suite fuer Orchester, op. 54, 1931; 42 pages; score, hardcover (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Phantastische Nachtmusik, op. 27, 69 pages; score, hardcover (Box 126, Folder 1)
      Date unknown.
    - Divertimento fuer Violine und Violoncello, op. 37, no. 1, 11 pages; score, paperback (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - Kleinstadtbilder, op. 49, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 3)
    - Poems to Martha, op. 66, 1943; 32 pages; score, paperback (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Fuge aus der Geographie, 1930; 2 photocopies of published score (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Vom sterbenden Rokoko, op. 16. nos. 1 and 3, 1910; 4 pages; Photocopy of published violin part (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Serenade, op. 25.revised ed., 1943; parts (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Collected Piano Works (Box 126, Folder 8)
      Burlesken, Op. 31. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1924 -- Drei Klavierstueke, Op. 32. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1925 -- Capriccetti, Op. 36. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1925 -- Tanz und Spielstueke, Op. 40. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1927 -- Sonate, Op. 47. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1928 -- Kleinstadtbilder, Op. 49. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1929 -- Fuenfmal zehn Etueden, Op. 55-59. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1931.
    - Burlesken, op. 31, 1924; 15 pages; paperback (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Choruses for Mixed Voices (Box 126, Folder 10)
      Cui Bono? -- The Lamb -- Extinquish My Eyes.
    - Folk Songs of the New Palestine. A Vatiach, 1939 (Box 169, Folder 14)
    - Folk Songs of the New Palestine. Tapuach Zahav., 1939 (Box 169, Folder 15)
  - Literary Works (Books), Subseries 2.
    Printed books by Toch.
    - Melodielehre, 1923; 182 pages; hardcover (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Die Chinesische Floete, 118 pages; paperback (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Der Faecher, 1930; 76 pages; paperback (Box 127, Folder 3-4)
      Libretto by F. Lion.
    - The Shaping Forces of Music, 1948; 245 pages; hardcover (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Shaping Forces (Box 127, Folder 6)
      Book jacket.
- Toch's Library: Books and Journals, Series 9.
  Printed books and journals. Boxes 128-163.
  - Books, Subseries 1.
    Books.
    - Knaurs Opernfuehrer, 1952; 541 pages (Box 128, Folder 1)
      Inscribed to Toch by the author.
    - Cohn, Arthur. The collector's Twentieth-century Music in the Western Hemisphere. Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott Company, 1961., 256 p. (Box 128, Folder 2)
      inscribed to Toch by the author
    - Turner, W. J. Mozart, the Man and his Works. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 1938., 458 p. (Box 128, Folder 3)
      inscribed to Toch by Georg Bassman
    - Bekker, Paul. Wagner, das leben im werke. Berlin: Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt Stuttgart, 1924., 588 p. (Box 128, Folder 4)
      inscribed to Toch by Eugene ___?
    - Hindemith, Paul. Unterweisung im Tonsatz. Mainz: B. Schott's Soehne, 1937., 252 p. (Box 128, Folder 5)
    - Eulenberg, Robert. Der Uebergang, eine tragoedie. Muenchen: Kurt Wolff Verlag, 1920., 131 p. (Box 128, Folder 6)
      poetic inscription by Robert Eulenberg
    - Dekker, Eduard Douwes (Multatuli). Max Havelaar. Leipzig: Otto Hendel, n.d., 295 p. (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Krishnamurti, J. Verstaendnis Sei Gesetz. Duesseldorf: Ernst Pieper Ring-Verlag, 1929., 32 p. (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Radbruch, Gustav. Einfuehrung in die Rechtswissenschaft. Leipzig: Verlag von Quelle & Meyer, 1919., 205 p. (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Agnon, S. J. Im Herzen der Meere und Andere Erzaehlungen. Zuerich: Manesse Verlag, 1966., 615 p. (Box 129, Folder 4)
    - Rueckert, Friedrich. Die Weisheit des Brahmanen. Leipzig: Verlag von S. Hirzel, 1896., 702 p. (Box 129, Folder 5)
      inscribed: to Toch on his Bar-Mizva, 1900.
    - Eeden, Frederik van. Der kleine Johannes III. Berlin: Schuster & Loeffler, 1906., 347 p. (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Eeden, Frederik van. Der Kleine Johannes I/II. Berlin: Schuster & Loeffler, 1906., 214 p. (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Coster, Charles de. Tyll Ulenspiegel und Lamm Goedzak. Jena: Eugen Diederichs, 1919., 605 p. (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - Aristophanes. Lysistrata. Leo Greiner, ed. Berlin: der Buecher des Deutschen Theaters, 1920., 123 p. (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Ellsan, Benno. Spanien Gesehen von Einem Kuenstler. Muenchen: Delphin-Verlag, 1926., 206 p. (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Bartsch, Rudolf Hans. Die Geschichte von der Hannerl und Ihren Liebhabern. Leipzig: Verlag von L. Staackmann, 1913., 392 p. (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Wildgans, Anton. Liebe. Leipzig: Verlag von L. Staackmann, 1916., 133 p. (Box 129, Folder 12)
    - Kerner, Dr. Med. Dieter. Mozarts Todeskrankheit. Berlin: Mainz, 1961., 32 p. (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Pfitzner, Hans. Futuristengefahr: Bei gelegenheit von Busoni's Aesthetik. Leipzig: Sueddeutsche Monatshefte, 1921., 51 p. (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Salzer, Felix. Strukturelles Hoeren: Der tonale Zusammenhang in der Musik. Band II. Wilhelmshaven: Otto Heinrich Noetzel, 1960., 349 p. (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold. Harmonielehre. Leipzig: Universal-Edition, 1911., 475 p. (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Reich, Willi. Mozarts Briefe. Zuerich: Manesse Verlag, 1948., 419 p. (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Rutz, Hans. Franz Schubert, Dokumente Seines Lebens und Schaffens. Muenchen: Verlag C. H. Beck, 1952., 214 p. (Box 130, Folder 6)
    - Wellesz, Egon. Arnold Schoenberg. Leipzig: E. P. Tal & Co. Verlag, 1921., 151 p. (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Stravinsky, Igor. Poetics of Music. Cambridge: Harvard University Press, 1947., 142 p. (Box 130, Folder 8)
    - Hanslick, Eduard. Fuenf Jahre Musik [1891-1895]. Berlin: Verein fuer Deutsche Litteratur, 1896., 402 p. (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Kerst, Friedrich. Schumman-brevier. Berlin: Verlegt bei Schuster & Loeffler, 1905., 234 p. (Box 130, Folder 9)
    - Ludwig, Emil. Beethoven, Life of a Conqueror. New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1943., 356 p. (Box 130, Folder 10)
    - Schweitzer, Albert. Aus Meiner Kindheit und Jugenzeit. Muenchen: C. H. Beck'sche Verlgasbuchhandlung, 1924., 63 p. (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Wagner, Richard. Saemtliche Schriften und Dichtungen. Leipzig: Breitkopf und Haertel, 1911. (Box 131)
      Six volumes.
    - Gedalge, Andre. Lehrbuch der Fuge. Braunschweig: Henry Litolff's Verlag, 1906 (?)., 377 p. (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - The Bible, King James version. Ernest Sutehrland Bates, ed. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1936. (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Kling, Professor H. Populaere Instrumentationslehre. Hannover: Louis Oertel Musikverlag, 1888 (?)., 147 p. (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Koechel, Dr. Ludwig Ritter von. W.A. Mozart Thematisches Verzeichnis Seiner Werke. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Haertel, 1905., 676 p. (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Kahn, Gordon. Hollywood on Trial: The Story of the Ten Who Were Indicted. Foreword by Thomas Mann. New York: Boni & Gaer, 1948., 229 p. (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Ziegler, Leopold. Ueberlieferung. Leipzig: Verlag Jakob Hegner, 1936., 558 p. (Box 134, Folder 2)
      Inscribed to Toch
    - Steinfeld, Julius I., M.D., Therapeutic Studies on Psychotics. Des Plaines: Forest Press-Publishers, 1951., 262 p. (Box 134, Folder 3)
      Inscribed to Ernst and Lilly Toch by the author.
    - MacDowell, Marian. The First Twenty Years of the MacDowell Colony. Peterborough: Transcript Printing Company, 1951., 16 p. (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Devare, Ulric. Gustav Mahler's Song of the Earth: An appreciation. London: Villiers Publications Ltd., 1960., 20 p. (Box 134, Folder 5)
      Introduction by Toch.
    - Jordan, Richard. Der Sprechende Hund. Stuttgart: Richard Jordon, n.d., 56 p. (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Kindermann, Henny. Lola: Der Sprechende Hund. Stuttgart: Verlag von Richard Jordan, 1927., 115 p. (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Bernhard, Emil. Die Jagd Gottes. Berlin: Volksbuehnen-Verlags und Vertriebs, n.d., 117 p. (Box 135, Folder 1)
      Inscribed with a poem signed by the author.
    - Thoreau, Henry David. Walden and other writings of Henry David Thoreau. New York: The Modern Library, 1937., 732 p. (Box 135, Folder 1)
      Inscribed on last page: "How glad I am to be able to share this book with both of you -- Clair." (Trotter)
    - Harley, Eugene. Woodrow Wilson Still Lives -- His World Ideals Triumphant. Los Angeles: Western Printing Company, 1944., 193 p. (Box 135, Folder 2)
    - Kessel, Martin. Gebaendigte Kurven: Gedichte. Frankfurt: Iris-Verlag, n.d., 75 p. (Box 135, Folder 2)
      Inscribed: to Toch by the author, 1927.
    - Knapp, Georg Friedrick. Aus der Jugend Eines Deutschen Gelehrten. Stuttgart: Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt, 1927., 185 p. (Box 135, Folder 3)
      Inscribed to Toch by Elly Heuss Knapp, 1933.
    - Stolper, Toni. Ein Leben in Brennpunkten Unserer Zeit: Gustav Stolper 1888-1947. Tuebingen: Rainer Wunderlich Verlag, 1960., 501 p. (Box 135, Folder 3)
    - Grimme, Adolf. Selbstbesinnung. Braunschweig: Verlag Georg Westermann, 1947., 227 p. (Box 135, Folder 4)
      Inscribed to Mrs. Toch by the author.
    - Korn, Peter Jona. Musikalische Umwelt Verschmutzung. Wiesbaden: Breitkopf & Haertel, 1975., 80 p. (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Arnold Schoenberg: Zum Fuenfzigsten Geburtstage. Wien: Sonderheft der Musicblaetter des Anbruch, 1924., 342 p. (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - Weyl, Hermann. Symmetrie. Basel: Birkhaeuser, 1955., 157 p. (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Zoff, Otto. Great Composers Through the Eyes of Their Contemporaries. New York: E. P. Dutton & Co. Inc., 1951., 510 p. (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Jadassohn, S. Lehrbuch des Einfachen. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Haertel, 1903., 43 p. (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Hadden, Cuthbert. The Master Musicians: Stories of Romantic Lives. London: T. N. Foulis, 1913., 254 p. (Box 136, Folder 6)
    - Uhde-Bernans, Hermann Spitzweg. Reime und bilder. Muenchen: Delphin-Verlag, n.d. (Box 137, Folder 1)
      inscribed: a quote on inside back cover and the initials M.K.
    - Bernhard, Emil. Hotel Eden Berlin: Volksbuehnen-Verlags-und Vertriebs-G.m.b.H., 1931., 85 p. (Box 137, Folder 2)
      Inscribed to Toch by author.
    - Grimme, Adolf. Vom wesen der romantik. Braunschweig: Verlag Georg Westermann, 1947., 84 p. (Box 137, Folder 3)
      Inscribed to Toch by the author (?)
    - Mann, Thomas. Nietszches Philosophie im Lichte Unserer Erfahrung. Stockholm: Bermann-Fischer Verlag, 1947. (Box 137, Folder 4)
      Inscribed to Mr. & Mrs. Toch from Thomas Mann.
    - Eulenberg, Herbert. Ernste schwaenke, vier einakter. Leipzig: Kurt Wolff Verlag, 1913. (Box 137, Folder 5)
      103 p.
    - Bericht: Ueber den Musikwissenschaftlichen Kongress in Basel. Leipzig: Druck und Verlag von Breitkopf & Haertel, 1925., 399 p. (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Ludwig, Emi.l Wilhelm der zweite. Berlin: Ernst Rowohlt Verlag, 1926. (Box 137, Folder 7)
      495 p.
    - Hay, Sara Hendersond. The Delicate Balance. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1951., 52 p. (Box 137, Folder 8)
      Inscribed: "For Ernst Toch, with the affectionate regards of Sally Lopatnikoff (Sara Henderson Hay) January 18, 1953."
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria. Die liebe der Magdalena. Leipzig: Im Insel-Verlag, 1919. (Box 137, Folder 9)
      (50 p.) inscribed
    - Skinner, Frank. Underscore. New York: Criterion Music Corp., 1950. (Box 137, Folder 10)
      239 p.
    - Devare, Ulric. Pieta. London: Villiers Publications Ltd., 1959. (Box 138, Folder 1)
      (19 p.) inscribed: "For the celebrated composer Ernst Toch with the kindest regards and the gratitude of Ulric Devare. February 25, 1960."
    - Schaeke, Gerhard. Kleine Portrats. Wuertt: Verlag "Die Arche" Itirsau, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 2)
      (71 p.) inscribed to Toch by author
    - Rilke, Rainer Maria. Die Briefe an Grafin Sizzo. 1921-1926. Wiesbaden: Im Insel-Verlag (Box 138, Folder 3)
      inscribed
    - Bethge, Hans. Lieder an eine kunstreiterin. Berlin: Gyldendalscher Verlag, 1922. (Box 138, Folder 5)
      41 p. inscribed to Toch by the author
    - Gero, Marcel. Uli Witewupp. attraktion in sechs aufzuegen. Berlin: Felix Bloch Erben, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 6)
      91 p. inscribed by Toch
    - Korngold, Julius. Child prodigy, Erich Wolfgang's years of childhood. New York: Willard Publishing Co., 1945. (Box 138, Folder 7)
      80 p. inscribed to Toch
    - Wuerz, Richard. Max Reger. Muenchen: Otto Halbreiter, 1920. (Box 138, Folder 8)
      Eine sammlung von studien aus dem kreise seiner persoenlichen schueler. Heft I: Regers harmonik von Dr. Hermann Grabner. 48 p. Inscribed to Toch
    - Devare, Ulric. Gustav Mahler's song of the earth (Das Lied von der Erde). London: Villiers Publications Ltd, 1960. (Box 138, Folder 9)
      An appreciation in commemoration of the one hundredth anniversary of the composer's birth. (Introduction by Ernst Toch.) 20 p.
    - Heuss-Knapp, Elly. Ausblick vom Muensterturm. Berlin: Hans Bott Verlag, n.d. (Box 138, Folder 10)
      (168 p.) inscribed: to Toch by the author 1935.
    - Devare, Ulric. Journey into harvest. London: Villiers Publications Ltd., 1961. (Box 138, Folder 11)
      (64 p.) inscribed: "For Ernst Toch with the highest regards and the greatest respect. God bless you always. Gratefully Ulric Devore. April 1961."
    - Doeblin, Alfred. November 1918 eine deutsche revolution. Muenchen: Im Verlag Karl Alber, 1949. (Box 138, Folder 12)
      Erzaehlwerk Heimkehr der Fronttruppen (497 p.) inscribed: signed by the author
    - Kaiser, Georg. Noli me tangere, stueck in zwei teilen. Potsdam: Gustav Kiepenheuer Verlag, 1922. (Box 139, Folder 1)
      81 p.
    - Poppen, Hermann. Max Reger. Leipzig: Breitkopf & Haertel, 1918. (Box 139, Folder 2)
      93 p.
    - Das zaubertheater von Medardus, Prokop und Sylvester. Leipzig: Kurt Wolff Verlag, 1915. (Box 139, Folder 3)
      mit einer einleitung von Franz Blei 304 p.
    - McNamara, Daniel I., ed. The ASCAP biographical dictionary of composers, authors and publishers. New York: Thomas Y. Crowell Co., 1952. (Box 139, Folder 4)
      L.C. # 52-7038 636 p.
    - Johannes Brahms. im Briefwechsel. Berlin: Gesellschaft m.b.h., 1908. (Box 139, Folder 5)
      mit Joseph Joachim, zweiter band 306 p.
    - Johannes Brahms. im briefwechsel. Berlin: Geschellschaft m.b.h., 1908. (Box 139, Folder 6)
      mit Joseph Joachim, erster band 329 p.
    - Kennan, Kent Wheeler. The technique of orchestration. New Jersey: Prentice-Hall, Inc., 1952. (Box 139, Folder 7)
      Prentice-Hall Music Series L.C. # 52-8604 321 p.
    - Endore, Guy. King of Paris. London: Cresset-Gollancz, 1956. (Box 140, Folder 1)
      A Novel based on the lines of Alexandre Dumas, father and son. (487 p.) inscribed: "To Ernst & Lilly. once in pencil and again in ink To Ernst & Lilly with the author's warmest wishes. Guy Endore."
    - Volksliederbuch fuer die jugend. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, 1930. (Box 140, Folder 2)
      Herausgegeben von der Staatlichen Kommission fuer das Volksliederbuch. Band I - Choere fuer gleiche Stimmen, Heft 1, Heft 3 Band II - Gemischte Choere, Heft 5, Heft 6 Band III - Einstimmige Lieder mit Begleitung, Heft 11, Heft 12, Heft 14 note: bound separately
    - Hensel, S. Die Familie Mendelssohn 1729-1847. Berlin: B. Behr's Verlag, 1908. (Box 141, Folder 1)
      nach briefen und tagebuechern. Fuenfzehnte Auflage, I. (483 p.)
    - Hensel, S. Die familie Mendelssohn 1729-1847. Berlin: B. Behr's Verlag, 1908. (Box 141, Folder 2)
      Nach briefen und tagebuechern. Fuenfzehnte auflage, II. 483 p.
    - Richard Strauss briefwechsel. Berlin: Paul Zsolnay, 1926. (Box 141, Folder 3)
      mit Hugo von Hofmannsthal 402 p.
    - Wellesz, Egon. Die neue instrumentation. Berlin: Max Hesses Verlag, 1928. (Box 141, Folder 4)
      Erste auflage (175 p.)
    - Wellesz, Egon. Die neue instrumentation. Berlin: Max Hesses Verlag, 1928. (Box 141, Folder 5)
      II. Teil: Das Orchester. Erste auflage. (183 p.)
    - Rolland, Ranain. Ludwig van Beethoven. Zuerich: Max Rascher, 1918. (Box 141, Folder 6)
      149 p.
    - Hummel, Walter. Nannerl, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozarts schwester. Zuerich: Amalthea-Verlag, 1952. (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Adler, Guido. Gustav Mahler. Leipzig: Universal Edition, 1916. (Box 142, Folder 2)
      106 p.
    - Ludwig van Beethovens briefe. Leipzig: Insel-Verlag, 1909. (Box 142, Folder 3)
      in ausmahl herausgegeben von Albert Leissmann 299 p.
    - Heinze, Leopold. Theoretisch = praftische musik = und harmonielehre. Breslau: Heinrich Handel's Verlag, 1895. (Box 142, Folder 4)
      nach paedagogischen grundfaessen 172 p.
    - Briefwechsel zwischen Wagner und Liszt. erste band. Leipzig: Breitkopf und Haertel, 1887. (Box 142, Folder 5)
      vom jahre 1841 bis 1853 298 p.
    - Briefwechsel zwischen Wagner und Liszt. zweiter band. Leipzig: Breitkopf und Haertel, 1887. (Box 142, Folder 6)
      vom jahre 1854 bis 1861 328 p.
    - Kreowski, Ernst und Fuchs, Edvard. Richard Wagner in der karikatur. Berlin: B. Behr's, 1907. (Box 142, Folder 7)
      mit sieben beilagen und 223 text-illustrationen 208 p.
    - Salzer, Felix. Strukturelles hoeren. Wilhelmshaven: Otto Heinrich Noetzel, 1960. (Box 143, Folder 1)
      der tonale zusammenhang in der musik I. 237 p.
    - Tolstoi, Leo N. Shakespeare: einte kritische studie. Hannover: Adolph Sponholtz Verlag, 1906. (Box 143, Folder 2)
      148 p.
    - Herz, Gerhard. Johann Sebastian Bach. Bern-Leipzig: Paul Haupt, 1936., 104 p. (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Rehfisch, Hans J. Nickel und die sechsunddreissig gerechten. Berlin: Oesterheld & Co. Verlag, 1925. (Box 143, Folder 4)
      Komoedie in drei Akten 85 p.
    - Wildgans, Anton. Armut ein trauerspiel von Anton Wildgans. Leipzig: Verlag von L. Staackmann, 1916. (Box 143, Folder 5)
      150 p.
    - Grabner, Hermann. Lehrbuch der musikalischen analyse. Leipzig: C. F. Kahnt. (Box 143, Folder 6)
      48 p.
    - Lortzing, G. A. Undine. Leipzig: C. F. Peters. (Box 143, Folder 7)
      240 p. score
    - Whitman, Walt. Leaves of grass. New York: Doubleday, Doran & Co., Inc., 1940. (Box 143, Folder 8)
      (316 p.)
    - Mann, Thomas. Doktor Faustus. Stockholm: Bermann-Fischer Verlag, 1947. (Box 144, Folder 1)
      inscribed: "To Ernst Toch, who has no need of the devil, a neighborly dedication from Thomas Mann." (772 p.)
    - Holmes, Edward. The life of Mozart. London: J. M. Dent & Sons, 1912. (Box 144, Folder 2)
      307 p. inscribed to Toch by his friend and pupil
    - Zum gedenken an Ernst Ludwig Heuss (Box 144, Folder 3)
      s. August 1910 bis 14. Februar 1967. Ansprache von Walter Bauer, 1967.
    - Guerster, Eugen. Nietzsche und die musik. Muenchen: Max Hueber Verlag, 1929. (Box 144, Folder 4)
      61 p. Inscribed to Toch
    - Klabund. Das Kirschbluetenfest. Speil nach dem japanischen. Wien: Phaidon-Verlag, 1927. (Box 144, Folder 5)
      (112 p.) inscribed: on cover page.
    - Mann, Thomas. Briefe 1937-1947. Kempten: S. Fischer Verlag, 1963. (Box 144, Folder 6)
      (765 p.)
    - Auszug des geistes. Bremer: Verlag B.C. Heye & Co., 1962. (Box 144, Folder 7)
      Bericht ueber eine Sendereihe. Bremer Beitraege IV. (231 p.) 3 copies
    - Moerike, Eduard. Mozart auf der Reise Nach Prag. Wien: Kunstverlag Anton Schroll & Co., n.d., 123 p. (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Bartsch, Rudolf Hans. Das deutsche leid. Leipzig: Verlag von L. Staackman, 1912. (Box 145, Folder 2)
      434 p.
    - Busoni, Ferruccio. Entwurf einer neuen aesthetik der tonkunst. Leipzig: Insel-Verlag; n.d. (Box 145, Folder 3)
      48 p. 2 copies